<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:42:16 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bill_frisell_anthology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:42:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bill_frisell_anthology/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, I got myself Bill Frisell: An Anthology - a collection of music written by guitarist Bill Frisell. I can&amp;rsquo;t really read music, so to me, it had been a coded book, which I keep in my collection as an object of curiosity. But there is something fascinating about it that even a non-musician can feel. It just seems &amp;hellip; profound. What amazes me about Bill Frisell&amp;rsquo;s written music is that each piece is just a couple of pages of simple notes and chords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/frame_cut_frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:01:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/frame_cut_frame/</guid>
      <description>One music album that I used to play a lot of was called Night of Short Lives. It was published in the 90&amp;rsquo;s under the artist name Frame Cut Frame. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to describe what kind of music it was. The publisher called it &amp;ldquo;unclassical music&amp;rdquo;, because the music had the classical texture, but not the classical form.
The CD was just one of those random things that I had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/yellowshark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 17:56:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/yellowshark/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I have a box of CDs that we hadn’t opened in maybe 10 years. We moved them across three continents because we don’t want to get rid of them, but with streaming services, we had very little reason to take them out of the box. We don’t even have a CD player in the house anymore. But there are treasures. We finally decided to take them out during the break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:16:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</guid>
      <description>I walked past Melbourne University’s Grainger Museum, which is dedicated to the Australian composer Percy Grainger. Kudos to the Wiggles for adapting one of his compositions into a children’s song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 11:05:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</guid>
      <description>A mini-review of the recently released &amp;ldquo;Miles Davis John Coltrane The Final Tour: The Bootleg Series, Vol. 6&amp;rdquo; album. The first track of the album, recorded in 1960 in a live show in Paris, documents a dramatic moment in the history of modern music. The European concert goers were expecting the dreamy world of Kind of Blue and some pleasant show tunes. They didn&amp;rsquo;t know that John Coltrane was going to unleash the furious sounds of the future to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several places in the music of Charles Ives</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/charles_ives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 21:38:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/charles_ives/</guid>
      <description>Charles Ives (1874–1954) is the quintessential American composer. Some of his compositions are as American as cherry pie. Take the Country Band March (1905), for example. It brings you straight to the turn-of-the century America:
It’s a collage of folk tunes, patriotic songs, and marching band music, but you only hear a melody briefly, and then it’s either interrupted rudely or mutated gracefully into another. Very often two or three motifs are played simultaneously so you can’t decide which one to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian wood(s) in Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:28:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Once I had a girl, or should I say, she once had me&amp;rdquo; sang John Lennon in Norwegian Wood (This Bird Has Flown), the second track of the classic Beatles album Rubber Soul. Released in 1965, this innovative composition, widely considered a Rock and Roll canon heralding the maturation of the relatively young art form, immortalized John Lennon&amp;rsquo;s extramarital affair with an unidentified woman, popularized the use of the sitar in Western music, and unintentionally led to the creation of one of the most clichéd imageries in Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
