<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jorge luis borges on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/jorge-luis-borges/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jorge luis borges on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:00:16 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/jorge-luis-borges/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2025_03_27_borges_pierre_menard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:00:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2025_03_27_borges_pierre_menard/</guid>
      <description>Pierre Menard, Author of the Quixote
1
Pierre Menard, Author of the Quixote is my favorite story by Jorge Luis Borges. Every time I read it I find something new to think about. The premise of this story is sheer absurdity: the narrator claims that his writer friend Pierre Menard had accomplished an unparalleled feat in literature, but this magnum opus was invisible to most people, because it was identical to selected chapters of Don Quixote by Cervantes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges_secret_miracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 23:23:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges_secret_miracle/</guid>
      <description>SPOILERS WARNING!
In Ficciones by Jorge Luis Borges, there is a story titled The Secret Miracle which I find particularly stimulating. The plot is centered on a writer who was sentenced to death. At the night before his execution, he begged God to grant him one more year of life so that he could finish writing an important piece of work. The next day, at the moment just before the bullet hit him, time suddenly stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges-chesteron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 23:20:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges-chesteron/</guid>
      <description>During the lockdown, I finally found the time to read the first volume of G.K. Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Father Brown stories. In general, I can&amp;rsquo;t say I like them as detective stories, because what I am looking for in this genre is brilliant deduction, and Father Brown doesn&amp;rsquo;t do that kind of thing. However, I was very impressed by a story titled The Sign of the Broken Sword. It&amp;rsquo;s a very unusual detective story, in which Father Brown analyzed the accepted narrative of a (fictional) historical event, and concluded that the overlooked inconsistencies could only mean one thing: the narrative was manufactured to cover up a deeper, tragic truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:28:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</guid>
      <description>I want to see writers use GitHub for literary experimentation. It can be a new form of ergodic literature. Imagine a novel released as a GitHub repo. Readers can read it. They can check out all the branches to explore parallel universes of alternative plots. They can read the revision history as a meta-novel, to learn about the writing process. And of course, they can make new versions of the novel by merging branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</guid>
      <description>A parody of Jorge Luis Borges&amp;rsquo;s essay &amp;ldquo;A New Refutation of Time&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;The Third Refutation of Ordinality&amp;rdquo;. Or maybe &amp;ldquo;10 Arguments Against Cardinality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
