<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>whimsical on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/whimsical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in whimsical on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 18:19:51 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/whimsical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So, I designed a clock face</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/clockface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 18:19:51 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/clockface/</guid>
      <description>I got the idea from a photo of a clock that I found randomly on eBay. I thought that it was a novelty clock with a very unusual industrial design, but after a little while, I realized that what happened was that the seller took the hands part, and placed them haphazardly on the clock face.
But it got me thinking, clock hands don&amp;rsquo;t have to rotate around the center, if they are mounted on rotating discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading comic books as brain lesions</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 23:10:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</guid>
      <description>I can’t be the only one who has trouble reading comic books. I have problems interpolating between the panels, and I find it hard to recognise the characters. In other words, I don’t know how one panel is related to the next, and I don’t know who’s who. Reading comic books to me is like a simulation of cortical lesions. It induces a mild form of akinetopsia(deficit in the perception of motion) and prosopagnosia (deficit in the perception of faces).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punning is no fun in Chinese</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:35:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</guid>
      <description>The Economist is probably not the best place to look for rigorous scholarship on comparative punnology, but a recent article did ask a very good question: Why English is such a great language for puns? I am not sure if the superiority of English in punning is that obvious, but the argument seems to be convincing:
For English is unusually good for puns. It has a large vocabulary and a rich stock of homophones from which puns can be made.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
