<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:01:53 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CV &amp; publications</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 14:50:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/publications/</guid>
      <description>For industry cv, see here. For academic cv, see here. For full list of publications, see Google Scholar For my peer reviews, see Publons  Recent presentations  2020: IBM Research Australia Seminar: Title: The traveling salesman in the brain: modeling the formation of topographical maps in the visual cortex using self-organization principles. 2019: New Advances in Biocomplexity Workshop (University of Sydney). Title: Artificial Intelligence and the eye: a window into health 2018: Monash University Machine Learning Symposium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Research</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 12:30:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/research/</guid>
      <description>1. AI applications in ophthalmology At clinics, monitoring the progression of glaucoma traditionally relies on visual field tests, which is unreliable and time consuming. In collaboration with clinical researchers at NYU, I investigated methods to infer visual field functions directly from scans of the retina, using 3D convolutional neural networks.
Publication:
 Yu et al. (in press) Estimating global visual field indices in glaucoma by combining macula and optic disc OCT scans using 3-dimensional convolutional neural networks Ophthalmology Glaucoma [link]  2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/about/</guid>
      <description>I received my Ph.D. from the Department of Cognitive Science of University of California San Diego.For my undergraduate degree, I studied Applied Mathematics at the National Chiao Tung University in Hsin-Chu, Taiwan.
I have had several different roles in science and research:
As an industry researcher in medical AI: I use machine learning and statistical methods to build AI applications in ophthalmology. I also have experience in managing data sharing and collaboration with academic researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:45:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>As an industry researcher in AI:  I use machine learning and statistical methods to build AI applications in ophthalmology. I have also filed two patents in medical AI. This paper, published in the clinical journal Ophthalmology Glaucoma, uses deep convolutional neural networks to assess the visual functions of glaucoma patients based on OCT scans of the retina.  The souce code, written in Python and Keras, Will be released as an open source package by IBM Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/frame_cut_frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:01:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/frame_cut_frame/</guid>
      <description>One music album that I used to play a lot of was called Night of Short Lives. It was published in the 90&amp;rsquo;s under the artist name Frame Cut Frame. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to describe what kind of music it was. The publisher called it &amp;ldquo;unclassical music&amp;rdquo;, because the music had the classical texture, but not the classical form.
The CD was just one of those random things that I had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hyperbolic_spirals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 23:19:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hyperbolic_spirals/</guid>
      <description>I found this in a box in the garage that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been opened in many years. I made it when I was a PhD student at UC San Diego. It&amp;rsquo;s a set of visual stimuli that I designed for a brain mapping experiment.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/brewster-bmm8cru2hysbehj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 08:53:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/brewster-bmm8cru2hysbehj/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Italo Calvino’s If on a winters night a traveller. One chapter is particularly interesting because it draws heavily on the imagery of optics (one of Calvino&amp;rsquo;s obsessions). It makes a reference to the 19th century British scientist David Brewster for his invention of the kaleidoscope. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read about Brewster before so I had to look him up. He was so much more than the inventor of kaleidoscope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 21:00:51 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading Thomas Pynchon’s novel V. about a month ago. I was thinking about writing a review, but what’s the point? Given its classic status, it has been analyzed to death. So just a couple of thoughts. This was Pynchon’s first novel, so we have to ask if it compares well to his later masterpieces. I think a novel worthy of Pynchon’s name must do two things: 1. It must induce a mindfuck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/yellowshark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 17:56:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/yellowshark/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I have a box of CDs that we hadn’t opened in maybe 10 years. We moved them across three continents because we don’t want to get rid of them, but with streaming services, we had very little reason to take them out of the box. We don’t even have a CD player in the house anymore. But there are treasures. We finally decided to take them out during the break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:04:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about the Emacs org-roam mode, and came across the Zettelkasten method of notetaking. I hadn’t seen this term before, but the idea of taking notes with cross-referenced index cards sounded familiar. Where did I read about it? Ah yes&amp;hellip; in Umberto Eco’s Foucault’s Pendulum, the main character Casaubon (an ex-academic who makes a living as a “detective of knowledge”) uses boxes of index cards to keep track of ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing the Emacs configuration script in org-mode: a simple example of literate programming</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/literate_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 14:16:59 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/literate_config/</guid>
      <description>Program like writers do Programming is traditionally seen as an exercise that translates human thoughts into a format that computers can understand. As a result, the ideas behind the program can become obscured and fragmented in the source code. This is why reading code requires so much mental effort. For me, reading code often feels like solving a puzzle, or reading modernist/postmodernist novels where events are narrated out of sequence. The concept of literate programming was introduced by Donald Knuth in the 80&amp;rsquo;s to address this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finger_lime_jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 17:56:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finger_lime_jam/</guid>
      <description>I bought this jam made from the native Australian plant finger lime Citrus australasica. I wasn’t expecting much because with enough sugar, all jams taste alike. But this is very different. At the first taste, it’s like a citrus but then the citrus taste is replaced by something very bitter. It’s weird. I will have no problem finishing this jar.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/review_count_zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:18:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/review_count_zero/</guid>
      <description>Finished William Gibson’s Count Zero. I like William Gibson. There are things that he did extremely well in this novel. But it doesn’t work. The three main threads of narrative are all interesting ideas by themselves, but they don’t add up to a meaningful big picture. In the end, I don’t understand why anything happened. I was planning to read Mona Lisa Overdrive after this one, but maybe not. The second half of Count Zero seems too clumsily written for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/new_rose_hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:14:05 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/new_rose_hotel/</guid>
      <description>Europe was a dead museum
 from William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s New Rose Hotel. Clearly an homage to William S. Burroughs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 12:10:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</guid>
      <description>So maybe you’ll get the Turing machine after your ass
 Count Zero by William Gibson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/about_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/about_site/</guid>
      <description>I started this site in 2018 to collect all my content in one place.
 The site is made with the Hugo static website generator, using a customized theme derived from the Pickles theme. I am working on supporting IndieWeb - an alternative approach to social networking based on open protocols. As of January 2021, this site supports IndieAuth authentication and service discovery. Content can be updated from micropub clients via a serverless application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How this website was built - a tutorial</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/website_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/website_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I started this website in 2018, because I wanted to collect all my content in one single place. I decided to built it with simple tools, so I could understand how everything works, and fix problems if needed. It&amp;rsquo;s a hobby like how some people like to build their own kitchens. Lots of tutorials are available on building personal websites, but I still want to write my own, because when I got started, I could never find one that explained every step needed to build a complete website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:55:01 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</guid>
      <description>I like this little episode in Umberto Eco&amp;rsquo;s Foucault&amp;rsquo;s Pendulum. In Chapter 53, one of the main characters Casaubon, a scholar of European history, unexpectedly ran into Inspector De Angelis in a library. He was surprised that the policeman checked out the same book that he was looking for. Why are you reading such an esoteric book? The policeman answered: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m off duty, I like to browse in libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:01:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</guid>
      <description>In V., Chapter 14, Pynchon made passing references to the Dreyfus Affair - a social controversy that divided France near the end of the 19th century. Just by coincidence, I read something about it earlier this year. The Father Brown story &amp;ldquo;The Duel of Dr Hirsch&amp;rdquo; by G.K. Chesterton is a very odd detective story, because it&amp;rsquo;s really a commentary on the Dreyfus Affairs.
The other historical figure that plays a more significant role in V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 09:37:39 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of an interesting book:Bedeviled: A Shadow History of Demons in Science, about thought experiments in science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 18:33:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recommended a book called &amp;ldquo;Computer Age Statistical Inference&amp;rdquo; by Efron &amp;amp; Hastie. I love the organization. Part I - classical stuff. Part II - Early computer-age methods. Part III - 21st century topics. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the type of textbooks that we need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:54:56 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</guid>
      <description>Idea: a Python dialect called Pynchon (after Thomas Pynchon). A pynchonic code is probably not very pythonic. Brevity is highly discouraged. Variable names should be all puns. In fact, Pynchon should be a concatenative language like Forth. This way, statements can be chained together into a longer and longer statement&amp;hellip; until the entire program is one single statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:42:34 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</guid>
      <description>Finished reading: V. by Thomas Pynchon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/humphrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:57:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/humphrey/</guid>
      <description>As a PhD student, I took a class in animal behaviour. I didn’t work very hard and have forgotten most of it. However, since I became a father, I have been thinking more about this class. One of the papers I read was the classic &amp;ldquo;The social function of the intellect&amp;rdquo; by Nicholas Humphrey, first published in 1976. The paper is packed with insightful analogies. For example, Humphrey offered an interesting interpretation of Robinson Crusoe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I run emacs in client/server mode under macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/emacs_clientserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 13:21:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/emacs_clientserver/</guid>
      <description>Many articles are available about running Emacs in client/server mode. However, when I tried to do it in my particular environment (macOS 11.0.1 Big Sur, using zsh), some tweaks were still needed. So I figured that it&amp;rsquo;s probably useful to document my setup.
In macOS, the Emacs executable is /Applications/Emacs.app/Contents/MacOS/Emacs. To run Emacs in its regular (non-server) operation mode, I defined two shell commands in .zshrc: emacs runs Emacs in GUI mode in a macOS window, whereas emacsnw runs Emacs in text mode within the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/incomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 01:31:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/incomplete/</guid>
      <description>This is a good article about Gödel’s incompleteness theorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:16:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</guid>
      <description>I walked past Melbourne University’s Grainger Museum, which is dedicated to the Australian composer Percy Grainger. Kudos to the Wiggles for adapting one of his compositions into a children’s song.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cbd_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 18:41:32 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cbd_again/</guid>
      <description>First time on Melbourne train since the pandemic!! I hadn’t seen this view since the middle of March.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 01:35:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>An obscure historical note from Thomas Pyhcon’s novel V.: there is a Chopin museum in the Spanish island of Mallorca, where you can see a cast of Frédéric Chopin’s hand. Chopin spent a winter there in 1838.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/generalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 18:36:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/generalisation/</guid>
      <description>I know that overgeneralisation is a controversial topic in the study of language acquisition, but here is an example: Zoe (4yo) used to say “even better”, but recently she started to say “even gooder”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/childcare_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 01:03:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/childcare_culture/</guid>
      <description>An interesting topic I studied in an animal behaviour class was about the concept of culture in animal societies. I started to think about the transmission of culture recently because I noticed that my 4yo daughter Zoe&amp;rsquo;s childcare playgroup has developed their own culture. When Zoe started to use a new word, I used to assumed that she learned it from the childcare educators. But recently I noticed that the children are teaching each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 01:32:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</guid>
      <description>I found this 2019 New York Times article about the fascinating work of French writer Georges Perec. Note that Donald Kunth called his Life: A User&amp;rsquo;s Manual “perhaps the greatest 20th century novel”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:28:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</guid>
      <description>I want to see writers use GitHub for literary experimentation. It can be a new form of ergodic literature. Imagine a novel released as a GitHub repo. Readers can read it. They can check out all the branches to explore parallel universes of alternative plots. They can read the revision history as a meta-novel, to learn about the writing process. And of course, they can make new versions of the novel by merging branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 23:29:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I rewrote my Emacs config script in the style of literate programming. Emacs has a markup language (org-mode) that makes it easy to mix rich text with code. I did it mostly out of curiosity. At that time, I didn’t know if writing something as trivial as a config file this way was a good idea in terms of practicality. After a month of tweaking, I am now convinced that It was helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/phewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:10:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/phewer/</guid>
      <description>We were watching a gun fight scene on TV. Zoe (4yo) asked &amp;ldquo;Why are there so many pew-ers?&amp;rdquo; Me: &amp;ldquo;what’s a pew-er?&amp;rdquo; She answered: &amp;ldquo;The thing that goes pew pew&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 23:32:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</guid>
      <description>In Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s first novel V., there is a subplot involving rhinoplasty. A surgeon in the story (“being a conservative”) refers to his own profession as the “Art of Tagliacozzi”. This is reference to the 16th century surgeon Gaspare Tagliacozzi, who pioneered surgical techniques for nasal reconstruction. He was a professor of anatomy at the Archiginnasio of Bologna, whose famous anatomical theatre houses a statue of Tagliacozzi holding a nose. I visited Bologna in 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:31:39 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/freedom/</guid>
      <description>Zoe is at an age (4yo) where she can randomly pick up really strange expressions. After biting into her lunch, she declared “it tastes like freedom! America!”. Apparently she learned it from a children’s cooking video on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 23:23:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</guid>
      <description>Bright Earth by Philip Ball is a remarkably multidisciplinary book about color. In a chapter about renaissance art, he described the technique of cangiantismo, which is most famously associated with the work of Michangelo. Wikipedia’s entry explains: “Cangiante is characterized by a change in color necessitated by an original color&amp;rsquo;s darkness or lightness limitation”. The effect is unnatural but it’s what fascinates me most about Michangelo’s paintings.
This article explains how the technique was used in contemporary art such as Monster Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/feynmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 01:23:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/feynmann/</guid>
      <description>Richard Feynman’s Integral Trick: I remember that in Surely You Are Joking, Mr. Feynman, Feynman talked about an obscure trick for doing integrals. What was he talking about? This article explains it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 01:13:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</guid>
      <description>It’s interesting that two favourite writers of mine had worked for big tech companies. Kurt Vonnegut worked for the PR department of GE. His portrayal of the genius scientist in Cat’s Cradle was based on his interview of Nobel Laureate Irving Langmuir of GE Research. Thomas Pynchon was a tech writer for Boeing. Yoyodyne, a defence contractor in The Crying of Lot 49, is a caricature of Boeing.
Dec 4th 2020 update: I also learned that William Gaddis worked for Kodak and IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</guid>
      <description> In other parts of Africa, you are aware of the earth beneath your feet, of the vegetation and the animals; all power seems concentrated in the earth. In North Africa the earth becomes the less important part of the landscape because you find yourself constantly raising your eyes to look at the sky. In the arid landscape the sky is the final arbiter. - Paul Bowles
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 01:17:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</guid>
      <description>Idea for a short story: linguists have been puzzled by a mysterious ancient manuscript written in a unknown language. It was deciphered after a computer scientist realized that the manuscript is a definition of the language that it’s written in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/p_adics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 01:09:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/p_adics/</guid>
      <description>An Infinite Universe of Number Systems - The p-adics seem to be a fanciful formalism of numbers. What’s interesting about it is that it provides a way to study an entire university of number systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:39:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</guid>
      <description>Anticipating the next release of macOS (10.16; Big Sur), I started to read the novel Big Sur by Jack Kerouac. It&amp;rsquo;s very interesting to me that in Chapter 12, Kerouac went to visit Neal Cassady, who was living in the Santa Clara Valley (more precisely, 1047 E. Santa Clara Street). So, in the late 50&amp;rsquo;s, Neal Cassady was practically living in today&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley. I had never associated with Silicon Valley with the counterculture movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, I designed a clock face</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/clockface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 18:19:51 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/clockface/</guid>
      <description>I got the idea from a photo of a clock that I found randomly on eBay. I thought that it was a novelty clock with a very unusual industrial design, but after a little while, I realized that what happened was that the seller took the hands part, and placed them haphazardly on the clock face.
But it got me thinking, clock hands don&amp;rsquo;t have to rotate around the center, if they are mounted on rotating discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/diderot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 10:56:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/diderot/</guid>
      <description> The loom for making stockings is one of the most complicated and rigorously logical machines that we have&amp;hellip; one could consider it as just one single piece of reasoning whose conclusion is the making of the stockings - Denis Diderot, quoted in Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s Collection of Sand.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Collection of Sand - essays by Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/calvino_sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/calvino_sand/</guid>
      <description>Collection of Sand is a collection of book reviews, exhibition reviews and travelogues that Italo Calvino wrote in the 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s. The quality varies. The best of them are unsurprisingly ekphrastic essays where Calvino described gardens, historical sites, and paintings in exquisite details. Those where he tried to regurgitate scientific or historical knowledge from academic books are less inspiring. But still, it is the variety of things that Calvino cared to write about that charms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hsin-Hao&#39;s UCSD CogSci office door photo archive</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/photo_archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 09:45:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/photo_archive/</guid>
      <description>                                         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who did the first computer simulation of a biological neuron?</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/hodgkinhuxley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 20:42:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/hodgkinhuxley/</guid>
      <description>Nobel laureates Alan Hodgkin and Andrew Huxley are sometimes called the fathers of computational neuroscience, because they developed the first mathematical theory to explain how neurons communicate with each other with electrical signals. I read in a textbook that when they published their model in 1952, all the numerical calculations were done manually, because the computer at Cambridge was not working. It was &amp;ldquo;computational&amp;rdquo; all right, but it was the labour intensive variety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hemingway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 23:26:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hemingway/</guid>
      <description>One of the productivity tips that I have found useful is oddly from Ernest Hemingway (hardly a man of high productivity). He said that he always worked to a point where he knew how to continue, and then stopped working for the day. This way, he always had a good start the next day. I read about it in an article on creativity but didn&amp;rsquo;t know where it was from. I just discovered it’s from Hemingway’s memoir A Movable Feast, in a chapter about his interactions with Gertrude Stein (&amp;ldquo;Miss Stein Instructs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make some spirals</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/spirals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 15:18:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/spirals/</guid>
      <description>Disk point picking is an elementary problem in geometry. To evenly distribute points on a disk, an intuitive idea is to sample pairs of numbers in polar coordinate (radius and angle) randomly from uniform distributions. After all, &amp;ldquo;uniformly&amp;rdquo; is just another word for &amp;ldquo;evenly&amp;rdquo;, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. When the points are sampled this way, the density of the dots fall off linearly with the distance to the origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</guid>
      <description>A parody of Jorge Luis Borges&amp;rsquo;s essay &amp;ldquo;A New Refutation of Time&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;The Third Refutation of Ordinality&amp;rdquo;. Or maybe &amp;ldquo;10 Arguments Against Cardinality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 11:05:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</guid>
      <description>A mini-review of the recently released &amp;ldquo;Miles Davis John Coltrane The Final Tour: The Bootleg Series, Vol. 6&amp;rdquo; album. The first track of the album, recorded in 1960 in a live show in Paris, documents a dramatic moment in the history of modern music. The European concert goers were expecting the dreamy world of Kind of Blue and some pleasant show tunes. They didn&amp;rsquo;t know that John Coltrane was going to unleash the furious sounds of the future to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient descent on a non-Euclidean surface</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/elastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 12:23:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/elastic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-the-salesman-travelling-on-foot-or-on-an-airplane&#34;&gt;Is the salesman travelling on foot or on an airplane?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article describes an experiment to develop a version of the elastic net algorithm that works on spherical surfaces. I needed it for a computational neuroscience problem, but for those who are mainly interested in machine learning, it also serves a simple and intuitive demonstration of using gradient descent on non-Euclidian surfaces. The Tensorflow source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hsinhaoyu/spherical_elastic_net&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I also made a youtube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uoZcTG_i2jQ&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; showing the algorithm in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popular Science</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:11:38 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/writing/</guid>
      <description>In addition to my website hhyu.org, I have been using Medium as the publishing platform for my general-audience writing. Interestingly, the most popular article that I have written has also been the most technical one. In How many photons get into your eyes?, I demonstrated how to estimate the number of photons emitted by various light sources. This article receives daily hits.
From 2014-2017, I wrote a series of articles for the Chinese speaking communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 13:09:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/gallery/</guid>
      <description>One the things that I enjoy the most in science is to communicate the findings in beautiful figures. I believe scientific figures should be effective (i.e., leave an impression) and efficient (i.e., highlight the main story). Here are some examples of the images that I have created (or helped to create) for research and teaching. Click on the images for brief explanations.
                                A &amp;#39;receptive field&amp;#39; map</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tori_amos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tori_amos/</guid>
      <description> I don’t believe you are leaving cause me and Charles Manson like the same ice cream - Tori Amos, Tears in Your Hands
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/blockchainjoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/blockchainjoke/</guid>
      <description>Anthropologists discovered that islanders in South Pacific have been using blockchains for thousands of years. All transactions are recorded by carving patterns on tree trunks, whose integrity is enforced by solving hard problems such as 12/5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/einsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/einsum/</guid>
      <description>Just discovered that python&amp;rsquo;s numerical package has a function for Einstein summation for tensors. In the past, you need that for cosmology. These days you use them for neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading comic books as brain lesions</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 23:10:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</guid>
      <description>I can’t be the only one who has trouble reading comic books. I have problems interpolating between the panels, and I find it hard to recognise the characters. In other words, I don’t know how one panel is related to the next, and I don’t know who’s who. Reading comic books to me is like a simulation of cortical lesions. It induces a mild form of akinetopsia(deficit in the perception of motion) and prosopagnosia (deficit in the perception of faces).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pendulum/</guid>
      <description>The plot of Umberto Eco&amp;rsquo;s novel Foucault&amp;rsquo;s Pendulum involves two publishers: Garamond and Manutius. Both names refer to figures in the history of printing: Claude Garamond designed the Garamond font in the 16th century, while Aldus Manutius was a famous 15th century printer who invented italic type, a few punctuation marks, and the pocketbook format. This might be a joke because both names are relatable to Apple. The Garamond font was used in Apple&amp;rsquo;s logo, and Aldus Co.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cobbler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:19:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cobbler/</guid>
      <description>This cobbler has remained in the same corner in Taipei for decades. The neighbourhood has experienced dramatic changes. Old apartments have been replaced by modern buildings. Traditional food stalls became hipster coffee shops. But this cobbler is apparently frozen in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/turing/</guid>
      <description> Turing once dreamed that he was a Turing machine. When he woke up, he wondered if it was him who dreamed of being a Turing machine, or if it was a Turning machine which dreamed that it was Turing - a koan from a programming book published in Taiwan)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/poincare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:45:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/poincare/</guid>
      <description>In a recent trip to Paris, my wife and I visited the Montparnasse Cemetery, hoping to find the tomb of the mathematician Évariste Galois. We were disappointed to learn that although Galois was indeed buried in the cemetery, he was buried in a common grave and the burial site can no longer be identified. However, we were delighted to have found the family tomb of Henri Poincaré.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/shutterspeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/shutterspeed/</guid>
      <description>What is the shutter speed of human vision? A new paper claims that at extremely low light condition, it can be as long as 0.6 second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/retina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/retina/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to see an optometrist. As he examined my eye with a strong light, I was amazed that I saw an image of the blood vessels on the retina. This phenomenon is called the entoptic image. It was first described by Purkinje about 200 years ago. I read about it in “How we perceive our own retina” by Kuno Kirschfeld (published in Proc. Bio. Sci.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punning is no fun in Chinese</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:35:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</guid>
      <description>The Economist is probably not the best place to look for rigorous scholarship on comparative punnology, but a recent article did ask a very good question: Why English is such a great language for puns? I am not sure if the superiority of English in punning is that obvious, but the argument seems to be convincing:
 For English is unusually good for puns. It has a large vocabulary and a rich stock of homophones from which puns can be made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:25:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</guid>
      <description>I saw this book in the Melbourne Rare Book Fair. To anyone who can read Chinese, this looks like the practice book of a young child starting to learn to write. The characters are intelligible, but the writer clearly has not mastered the basic principles. If Chinese characters are people, these little guys are seriously deformed. Some have really big heads, some have tiny feet, most of them look like zombies walking with their body parts dangling, ready to fall off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:18:50 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</guid>
      <description>Michel Foucault’s Madness and Civilization opens with the poetic imagery of Ship of Fools. But what is the ship of fools? Apparently it all started with this book. I saw it in an exhibition of books sharing the theme of traveling at the library of Monash University. This is the latin edition of Ship of Fools by German humanist Sebastian Brant, published in 1497. The illustrations are by Albretch Durer (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which department threw out a freaking VAX?</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:01:17 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vax/</guid>
      <description>On university corridors, you inevitably see old equipments lying around. But which department threw out an entire freaking VAX?
    Those must be the famous &amp;ldquo;blinkenlights&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 18:48:32 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</guid>
      <description>This is the famous world map by the 15th century monk Fra Mauro. I saw it in Museo Galileo in Florence. Unfortunately it was a replica. The real thing is in Venice. I found it very difficult to recognize landmarks on the map because the orientation is very different from our modern convention. North is down. South is up.
         Here’s a puzzle: What’s this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipitous photoshopping</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photoshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 23:55:20 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photoshop/</guid>
      <description>The unusually thick glasses on the windows of the Old Art building in Melbourne University seem to be hand-polished, whose uneven surfaces naturally distort the view into an American expressionist painting.
     The historic building of the Drum Theatre in Dandenong, Victoria was reflected on a modern office building across the road. The reflective windows reconfigured the image into an incongruent mosaic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereoscopic photography on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 23:45:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2ds/</guid>
      <description>I received a Nintendo 2DS as a gift. The 2DS is a downgraded version of the Nintendo 3DS handheld game console. To cut price (2DS retails at about $150 AUD), Nintendo removed the 3D display but interestingly it still has a pair of front facing cameras. The photos are saved into the .MPO format, and can be loaded and processed by many programs running on computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ingenious sundial of Professor Moppert</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/sundial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 22:06:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/sundial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installed on the northern wall of the Monash University student centre (Melbourne) is a curious geometrical object. If you don’t pay close attention, you might think it’s just a decorative sculpture. But it is actually a functional sundial — conceived and constructed by the mathematician Carl Moppert in the 80’s. This design appears to be unique. I browsed through many photos on Instagram tagged with #sundial, and I couldn’t find another one that looks quite like it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several places in the music of Charles Ives</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/charles_ives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 21:38:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/charles_ives/</guid>
      <description>Charles Ives (1874–1954) is the quintessential American composer. Some of his compositions are as American as cherry pie. Take the Country Band March (1905), for example. It brings you straight to the turn-of-the century America:
  It’s a collage of folk tunes, patriotic songs, and marching band music, but you only hear a melody briefly, and then it’s either interrupted rudely or mutated gracefully into another. Very often two or three motifs are played simultaneously so you can’t decide which one to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A magic trick based on Fourier transform</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/fourierdemonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:40:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/fourierdemonstration/</guid>
      <description>Fourier analysis says that complex patterns can be created by adding up a large number of patterns as simple as sinusoidal waves. To make the idea more concrete, I like to use the following analogy in teaching: Imagine that you lived in the early 19th century. If you wanted to listen to a symphony, the only way to make it happen was to hire a few dozen highly-trained musicians to perform it for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:20:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/elm/</guid>
      <description>Have I neglected the backyard garden this much in the last few weeks? This morning when I opened the backdoor, I was surprised to see the grounds covered by mysterious coin-shaped objects. They were clearly seeds — seeds wearing papery, gossamer skirts. Sure, I have seen them before, but not so many all at once.
         They parachuted from my neighbor’s golden elm tree - an elm native to northern America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lens</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:08:07 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/lens/</guid>
      <description>     The lens is the component in the eye that reflects light. They are not always shape liked pancakes or magnifying glasses. In small mammals, the lens is very often looks like the chewy tapioca balls in Asian boba milk tea.
             Primate lenses are more like magnifying glasses:
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/word_puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:03:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/word_puzzle/</guid>
      <description>A friend told me about Su Hui&amp;rsquo;s Star Gauge. It is is a matrix poem composed in the 4th century by the Chinese poetess Su Hui. The characters are arranged in a 29x29 matrix. The submatrices can be read in different directions, producing (apparently) 3000 poems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panoramic</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 01:38:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/panorama/</guid>
      <description>Along the River During the Qingming Festival (清明上河圖) is a 12th-century classic Chinese painting depicting the imperial capital on a particularly busy day. Painted on a long scroll, the &amp;ldquo;panorama&amp;rdquo; is too wide to be appreciated in its entirity. The viewers are invited to view only a small section of the painting at the time and immerse themselves in the details.
    I have been interested in duplicating this effect with photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The old man and the vacuum tubes</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/akihabara/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:59:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/akihabara/</guid>
      <description>During a trip to Tokyo in 2013, I found an opportunity to visit the Akihabara district. This area is world famous for its high concentration of shops selling the latest models of computers, game consoles, gadgets, and other geeky items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian wood(s) in Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:28:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Once I had a girl, or should I say, she once had me&amp;rdquo; sang John Lennon in Norwegian Wood (This Bird Has Flown), the second track of the classic Beatles album Rubber Soul. Released in 1965, this innovative composition, widely considered a Rock and Roll canon heralding the maturation of the relatively young art form, immortalized John Lennon&amp;rsquo;s extramarital affair with an unidentified woman, popularized the use of the sitar in Western music, and unintentionally led to the creation of one of the most clichéd imageries in Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curb your nostalgic Japanese childhood enthusiasm</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/maruko/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:09:14 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/maruko/</guid>
      <description>You don’t have to be a New York Jew to be neurotic. Being a Japanese little girl will do.
Chibi Maruko-Chan is a popular Japanese cartoon for children. It is about the life of a Japanese girl in elementary school. On the surface it’s a typical saccharine sweet Japanese show about growing up. Maruko is as adorable as can be. Her nickname Maruko means “chubby” and her last name means &amp;ldquo;cherry&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The seeds of quandong</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/quandong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 01:29:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/quandong/</guid>
      <description>There is a desert quandong tree (Santalum acuminatum), a native Australian plant, on campus. I walked past it for months without paying any attention to it until it started to bear fruits. Its bell-like fruits look like decorations of the Christmas tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many photons get into your eyes?</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 20:31:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photons/</guid>
      <description>A recent paper shows that our vision is so sensitive to light that human subjects can detect the presence of one single photon shot into their retinas. While scientists have been trying to establish the lower limit of visual sensitivity for a very long time, and it is generally accepted that a small number of photons are sufficient for detection since the 40’s, new advances in quantum optics finally allow us to manipulate light at single photon precision, and it is the first time that direct evidence for single photon sensitivity is demonstrated in a psychological experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The marmoset visual area DM for dummies</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/areadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 20:07:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/areadm/</guid>
      <description>The visuotopic map of the marmoset dorsomedial visual cortex (area DM; see references) is sufficiently complex that it is probably worthwhile to design a few visual aides to make it more intuitive. The figure above is my first attempt. In this figure, DM is divided into three segments, with the most medial segment representing central upper visual field (nose and eye of Sir Isaac Newton), the middle segment representing the entire lower visual field, and the medial segment representing the peripheral upper visual field (the forehead and hair of Newton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The retinotopic map of marmoset V1</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/marmosetv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 18:51:42 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/marmosetv1/</guid>
      <description>I created this figure to illustrate the retinotopic map of the primary visual cortex of the marmoset. The eccentricity contours are plotted in red, and polar angles are in blue. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create it in 3D so that you can rotate it around and see it from different angles. This is how you do it:
  Download ParaView, the open source 3D data visualization package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mangarevan arithmetic</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/mangarevan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 18:37:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/mangarevan/</guid>
      <description>PNAS recently published a cognitive anthropology paper titled Mangarevan invention of binary steps for easier calculation. The paper describes an arithmetic system that had been used for hundreds of years by islanders living in Mangareva (a small island in French Polynesia) for the purpose of “counting a small group of highly valued objects such as turtles, fish, coconuts, octopuses, and breadfruits”. This system is not too different from the decimal system that we’re using today, except that a number in the Mangarevan language can contain a small segment of binary code, which employs four numerals to represent 10 multiplied by the first four powers of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/don_quixote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/don_quixote/</guid>
      <description> The reason of the unreason with which my reason is afflicted so weakens my reason that with reason I murmur at your beauty - Don Quixote
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color-vision-historical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 19:04:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color-vision-historical/</guid>
      <description>What was the first time that we know that non-human animals have color vision? From what I can find, the first person who scientifically came to that conclusion was John Lubbock in 1888. What was so strange about it was that he studied Daphnia - a plankton (!). He discovered that the plankton was attracted to yellow light, but not to white light. Lubbock also reasoned that insects must have color vision, but was not able to scientifically demonstrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/journal/</guid>
      <description>We need a journal that publishes papers in the style of the 18th century: long title, flowery prose, kudos to King and church, and extreme modesty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/visual_cortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/visual_cortex/</guid>
      <description>What is known as the visual cortex today was thought to be the site of &amp;ldquo;philoprogenitivty” (parental love) in phrenology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</guid>
      <description> Really. Hey, like Godzilla always sez to Mothra — why don’t we go eat some place? — Inherent Vice by Thomas Pynchon
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</guid>
      <description>Choose your next private key carefully, Mr. Bond. It may be your last. Do you expect me to talk? No. I expect you to prime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</guid>
      <description> No worries, it’s on the house, as the TV antenna man always sez — Thomas Pynchon in Inherent Vice
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar opposite</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/polar-opposite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 17:28:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/polar-opposite/</guid>
      <description>This figure illustrates the direction tuning curves of two motion sensitive neurons recorded in the primary visual cortex. The two neurons were so close to each other that their activities could be picked up by the same electrode. Interestingly they preferred polar opposite directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/ground-squirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 18:26:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/ground-squirrel/</guid>
      <description>I took these photos for a research project while I was a student at UC San Diego. They are the skull and the brain of the California ground squirrel (Spermophilus beecheyi)
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PSY3310/Human vision as frequency filters</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edupsy3310-fourier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:32:20 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edupsy3310-fourier/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrations:  The reconstruction of Mona Lisa video. A blog post I wrote about the Fourier transform trick. Youtube video: Nobel laureates David Hubel and Torsten Wiesel recording neurons in cat&amp;rsquo;s V1.  Suggested readings: Fourier transform  An introduction to two-dimensional fast Fourier transforms and their applications by Rzeszotarski et al. (1983). Fourier transforms and frequency-domain processing (Chapter 5 of Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing: A Practical Approach with Examples in Matlab by Solomon &amp;amp; Breckon, 2011)  Suggested readings: programming  See this web page from UCSB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: RAD2092/Physiology of Visual Pathways</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-visual-cortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:26:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-visual-cortex/</guid>
      <description> Central disorders of vision in humans by Girkin &amp;amp; Miller (2001): a review of what happens if different parts of the visual cortex are damaged. &amp;ldquo;Superimposed hemifields in primary visual cortex of achiasmic individuals&amp;rdquo; by Sinha &amp;amp; Meng (2012, Neuron 75): Newton vs. Descartes on the organization of the optic chiasm. Youtube video demonstrating how Hubel &amp;amp; Wiesel mapped V1 receptive fields.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: RAD2092/The eye and the retina</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:23:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-eye/</guid>
      <description> Animal Eyes by Land &amp;amp; Nilsson is a very nice little book about the fascinating variety of eye structures found in nature. Youtube video about the &amp;ldquo;connectome&amp;rdquo; of the retina  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: RAD2092/The Cerebral Cortex</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-cortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:13:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/edurad2092-cortex/</guid>
      <description>General  Is the human cortex exceptionally large? See Herculano-Houzel (2009) The human brain in numbers: a linearly scaled-up primate brain. Frontiers in Neuroscience 3, e31. [Tenor sings opera during craniotomy](Tenor sings opera during craniotomy): I just think this is quite fascinating.  &amp;ldquo;Language areas&amp;rdquo;  The history of Broca&amp;rsquo;s area: Dronkers et al. (2007) Neuroimaging of Language: Why hasn&amp;rsquo;t a clear picture emerged? Fedorenko &amp;amp; Kanwisher (2009) Language and Linguistics Compass 3, 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PHY3012/Plasticity in the visual system in development</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3012-plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:02:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3012-plasticity/</guid>
      <description>Interesting  A man with only half a brain A study of a man who recovered vision after decades of being blind: Fine et al. (2003) Long-term deprivation affects visual perception and cortex. Nat. Neurosci. 6, p915. How Utter Darkness Could Heal Lazy Eye: related to ocular dominance critical period. Giving blind people sight illuminates the brain’s secrets  General review  Anderson et al (2011) Do children really recover better?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PHY3111/Prac</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3111-prac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 13:56:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3111-prac/</guid>
      <description>More about extracellular recording  Wikipedia entry about single-unit recording Extracellular single-unit Recording Methods: a paper by Humphrey &amp;amp; Schmidt  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PHY3111/Color Vision</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3111-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 13:33:14 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/eduphy3111-color/</guid>
      <description>Interesting articles  Impossible colours: You can experience colours that you have never seen before. Some women are tetrachromatic. They can see more colours than most people can. The rainbow does not contain all the colours that we can see. For example, magenta.  Dressgate  Disrobing the dress:A very detailed webpage about the dress. Lessons from the dress: by vision scientist Pascal Wallisch. The science of why no one agrees on the color of this dress: an article on Wired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary materials for undegraduate lectures</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 13:20:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/teaching/</guid>
      <description>The followings are for students who want to learn more about the topics that I talk about in lectures. They are optional readings. You won&amp;rsquo;t be tested on them.
PHY3111: Sensation and Movement (2014, 2015)  Colour Vision Prac class: Recording Electrophysiological Signals (cockroach recordings)  PHY3012: Integrative Neuroscience - Neuron to Brain (2015)  Plasticity in the visual system in development  RAD2092: Radiologic Biology 4 and Sectional Anatomy (2012-)  Organization of the Cerebral Cortex The Eye and the Retina Physiology of Visual Pathways  PSY3310: Introduction to Computational Neuroscience (2016, 2017)  Human vision as frequency filters The neural basis of frequency processing  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
