<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pun on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/pun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pun on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:35:30 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/pun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Punning is no fun in Chinese</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 23:35:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/chinese_punning/</guid>
      <description>The Economist is probably not the best place to look for rigorous scholarship on comparative punnology, but a recent article did ask a very good question: Why English is such a great language for puns? I am not sure if the superiority of English in punning is that obvious, but the argument seems to be convincing:
 For English is unusually good for puns. It has a large vocabulary and a rich stock of homophones from which puns can be made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian wood(s) in Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:28:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/norwegian/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Once I had a girl, or should I say, she once had me&amp;rdquo; sang John Lennon in Norwegian Wood (This Bird Has Flown), the second track of the classic Beatles album Rubber Soul. Released in 1965, this innovative composition, widely considered a Rock and Roll canon heralding the maturation of the relatively young art form, immortalized John Lennon&amp;rsquo;s extramarital affair with an unidentified woman, popularized the use of the sitar in Western music, and unintentionally led to the creation of one of the most clichéd imageries in Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</guid>
      <description> Really. Hey, like Godzilla always sez to Mothra — why don’t we go eat some place? — Inherent Vice by Thomas Pynchon
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</guid>
      <description>Choose your next private key carefully, Mr. Bond. It may be your last. Do you expect me to talk? No. I expect you to prime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</guid>
      <description> No worries, it’s on the house, as the TV antenna man always sez — Thomas Pynchon in Inherent Vice
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>