<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>story on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in story on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 23:23:18 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges_secret_miracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 23:23:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges_secret_miracle/</guid>
      <description>SPOILERS WARNING!
In Ficciones by Jorge Luis Borges, there is a story titled The Secret Miracle which I find particularly stimulating. The plot is centered on a writer who was sentenced to death. At the night before his execution, he begged God to grant him one more year of life so that he could finish writing an important piece of work. The next day, at the moment just before the bullet hit him, time suddenly stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:28:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</guid>
      <description>I want to see writers use GitHub for literary experimentation. It can be a new form of ergodic literature. Imagine a novel released as a GitHub repo. Readers can read it. They can check out all the branches to explore parallel universes of alternative plots. They can read the revision history as a meta-novel, to learn about the writing process. And of course, they can make new versions of the novel by merging branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 01:17:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</guid>
      <description>Idea for a short story: linguists have been puzzled by a mysterious ancient manuscript written in a unknown language. It was deciphered after a computer scientist realized that the manuscript is a definition of the language that it’s written in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
