<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Micros on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micros on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:04:13 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/micro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:04:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about the Emacs org-roam mode, and came across the Zettelkasten method of notetaking. I hadn’t seen this term before, but the idea of taking notes with cross-referenced index cards sounded familiar. Where did I read about it? Ah yes&amp;hellip; in Umberto Eco’s Foucault’s Pendulum, the main character Casaubon (an ex-academic who makes a living as a “detective of knowledge”) uses boxes of index cards to keep track of ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/test_quill-mrryhluzfztywu0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 09:57:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/test_quill-mrryhluzfztywu0/</guid>
      <description>Testing testing. Posting from Quill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 12:10:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</guid>
      <description>“So maybe you’ll get the Turing machine after your ass”
 Count Zero by William Gibson.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:55:01 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</guid>
      <description>I like this little episode in Umberto Eco&amp;rsquo;s Foucault&amp;rsquo;s Pendulum. In Chapter 53, one of the main characters Casaubon, a scholar of European history, unexpectedly ran into Inspector De Angelis in a library. He was surprised that the policeman checked out the same book that he was looking for. Why are you reading such an esoteric book? The policeman answered: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m off duty, I like to browse in libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:01:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</guid>
      <description>In V., Chapter 14, Pynchon made passing references to the Dreyfus Affair - a social controversy that divided France near the end of the 19th century. Just by coincidence, I read something about it earlier this year. The Father Brown story &amp;ldquo;The Duel of Dr Hirsch&amp;rdquo; by G.K. Chesterton is a very odd detective story, because it&amp;rsquo;s really a commentary on the Dreyfus Affairs.
The other historical figure that plays a more significant role in V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 09:37:39 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of an interesting book:Bedeviled: A Shadow History of Demons in Science, about thought experiments in science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:47:02 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/wine/</guid>
      <description>Wine made from grapes infected by fungi?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/githubtrigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:44:40 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/githubtrigger/</guid>
      <description>My site is hosted on AWS S3. I was planning to use Travis to setup a pipeline, such that every time I push a new post to GitHub, it automatically generates the site and syncs with S3. The problem was that Travis’ cost structure seems to have changed, so it became less appealing. I gave GitHub Actions a shot. It worked very well. It’s easy to use and easy to program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 18:33:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recommended a book called &amp;ldquo;Computer Age Statistical Inference&amp;rdquo; by Efron &amp;amp; Hastie. I love the organization. Part I - classical stuff. Part II - Early computer-age methods. Part III - 21st century topics. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the type of textbooks that we need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:54:56 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</guid>
      <description>Idea: a Python dialect called Pynchon (after Thomas Pynchon). A pynchonic code is probably not very pythonic. Brevity is highly discouraged. Variable names should be all puns. In fact, Pynchon should be a concatenative language like Forth. This way, statements can be chained together into a longer and longer statement&amp;hellip; until the entire program is one single statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:42:34 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</guid>
      <description>Finished reading: V. by Thomas Pynchon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/humphrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:57:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/humphrey/</guid>
      <description>As a PhD student, I took a class in animal behaviour. I didn’t work very hard and have forgotten most of it. However, since I became a father, I have been thinking more about this class. One of the papers I read was the classic &amp;ldquo;The social function of the intellect&amp;rdquo; by Nicholas Humphrey, first published in 1976. The paper is packed with insightful analogies. For example, Humphrey offered an interesting interpretation of Robinson Crusoe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/incomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 01:31:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/incomplete/</guid>
      <description>This is a good article about Gödel’s incompleteness theorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:16:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/granger/</guid>
      <description>I walked past Melbourne University’s Grainger Museum, which is dedicated to the Australian composer Percy Grainger. Kudos to the Wiggles for adapting one of his compositions into a children’s song.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cbd_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 18:41:32 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cbd_again/</guid>
      <description>First time on Melbourne train since the pandemic!! I hadn’t seen this view since the middle of March.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 01:35:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>An obscure historical note from Thomas Pyhcon’s novel V.: there is a Chopin museum in the Spanish island of Mallorca, where you can see a cast of Frédéric Chopin’s hand. Chopin spent a winter there in 1838.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/generalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 18:36:23 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/generalisation/</guid>
      <description>I know that overgeneralisation is a controversial topic in the study of language acquisition, but here is an example: Zoe (4yo) used to say “even better”, but recently she started to say “even gooder”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/childcare_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 01:03:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/childcare_culture/</guid>
      <description>An interesting topic I studied in an animal behaviour class was about the concept of culture in animal societies. I started to think about the transmission of culture recently because I noticed that my 4yo daughter Zoe&amp;rsquo;s childcare playgroup has developed their own culture. When Zoe started to use a new word, I used to assumed that she learned it from the childcare educators. But recently I noticed that the children are teaching each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 01:32:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</guid>
      <description>I found this 2019 New York Times article about the fascinating work of French writer Georges Perec. Note that Donald Kunth called his Life: A User&amp;rsquo;s Manual “perhaps the greatest 20th century novel”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:28:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</guid>
      <description>I want to see writers use GitHub for literary experimentation. It can be a new form of ergodic literature. Imagine a novel released as a GitHub repo. Readers can read it. They can check out all the branches to explore parallel universes of alternative plots. They can read the revision history as a meta-novel, to learn about the writing process. And of course, they can make new versions of the novel by merging branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 23:29:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I rewrote my Emacs config script in the style of literate programming. Emacs has a markup language (org-mode) that makes it easy to mix rich text with code. I did it mostly out of curiosity. At that time, I didn’t know if writing something as trivial as a config file this way was a good idea in terms of practicality. After a month of tweaking, I am now convinced that It was helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/phewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:10:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/phewer/</guid>
      <description>We were watching a gun fight scene on TV. Zoe (4yo) asked &amp;ldquo;Why are there so many pew-ers?&amp;rdquo; Me: &amp;ldquo;what’s a pew-er?&amp;rdquo; She answered: &amp;ldquo;The thing that goes pew pew&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 23:32:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</guid>
      <description>In Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s first novel V., there is a subplot involving rhinoplasty. A surgeon in the story (“being a conservative”) refers to his own profession as the “Art of Tagliacozzi”. This is reference to the 16th century surgeon Gaspare Tagliacozzi, who pioneered surgical techniques for nasal reconstruction. He was a professor of anatomy at the Archiginnasio of Bologna, whose famous anatomical theatre houses a statue of Tagliacozzi holding a nose. I visited Bologna in 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:31:39 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/freedom/</guid>
      <description>Zoe is at an age (4yo) where she can randomly pick up really strange expressions. After biting into her lunch, she declared “it tastes like freedom! America!”. Apparently she learned it from a children’s cooking video on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 23:23:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</guid>
      <description>Bright Earth by Philip Ball is a remarkably multidisciplinary book about color. In a chapter about renaissance art, he described the technique of cangiantismo, which is most famously associated with the work of Michangelo. Wikipedia’s entry explains: “Cangiante is characterized by a change in color necessitated by an original color&amp;rsquo;s darkness or lightness limitation”. The effect is unnatural but it’s what fascinates me most about Michangelo’s paintings.
This article explains how the technique was used in contemporary art such as Monster Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/feynmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 01:23:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/feynmann/</guid>
      <description>Richard Feynman’s Integral Trick: I remember that in Surely You Are Joking, Mr. Feynman, Feynman talked about an obscure trick for doing integrals. What was he talking about? This article explains it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 01:13:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</guid>
      <description>It’s interesting that two favourite writers of mine had worked for big tech companies. Kurt Vonnegut worked for the PR department of GE. His portrayal of the genius scientist in Cat’s Cradle was based on his interview of Nobel Laureate Irving Langmuir of GE Research. Thomas Pynchon was a tech writer for Boeing. Yoyodyne, a defence contractor in The Crying of Lot 49, is a caricature of Boeing.
Dec 4th 2020 update: I also learned that William Gaddis worked for Kodak and IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</guid>
      <description> In other parts of Africa, you are aware of the earth beneath your feet, of the vegetation and the animals; all power seems concentrated in the earth. In North Africa the earth becomes the less important part of the landscape because you find yourself constantly raising your eyes to look at the sky. In the arid landscape the sky is the final arbiter. - Paul Bowles
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 01:17:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/story_language/</guid>
      <description>Idea for a short story: linguists have been puzzled by a mysterious ancient manuscript written in a unknown language. It was deciphered after a computer scientist realized that the manuscript is a definition of the language that it’s written in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/p_adics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 01:09:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/p_adics/</guid>
      <description>An Infinite Universe of Number Systems - The p-adics seem to be a fanciful formalism of numbers. What’s interesting about it is that it provides a way to study an entire university of number systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:39:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</guid>
      <description>Anticipating the next release of macOS (10.16; Big Sur), I started to read the novel Big Sur by Jack Kerouac. It&amp;rsquo;s very interesting to me that in Chapter 12, Kerouac went to visit Neal Cassady, who was living in the Santa Clara Valley (more precisely, 1047 E. Santa Clara Street). So, in the late 50&amp;rsquo;s, Neal Cassady was practically living in today&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley. I had never associated with Silicon Valley with the counterculture movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/diderot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 10:56:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/diderot/</guid>
      <description> The loom for making stockings is one of the most complicated and rigorously logical machines that we have&amp;hellip; one could consider it as just one single piece of reasoning whose conclusion is the making of the stockings - Denis Diderot, quoted in Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s Collection of Sand.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hemingway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 23:26:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/hemingway/</guid>
      <description>One of the productivity tips that I have found useful is oddly from Ernest Hemingway (hardly a man of high productivity). He said that he always worked to a point where he knew how to continue, and then stopped working for the day. This way, he always had a good start the next day. I read about it in an article on creativity but didn&amp;rsquo;t know where it was from. I just discovered it’s from Hemingway’s memoir A Movable Feast, in a chapter about his interactions with Gertrude Stein (&amp;ldquo;Miss Stein Instructs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/borges/</guid>
      <description>A parody of Jorge Luis Borges&amp;rsquo;s essay &amp;ldquo;A New Refutation of Time&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;The Third Refutation of Ordinality&amp;rdquo;. Or maybe &amp;ldquo;10 Arguments Against Cardinality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 11:05:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/miles/</guid>
      <description>A mini-review of the recently released &amp;ldquo;Miles Davis John Coltrane The Final Tour: The Bootleg Series, Vol. 6&amp;rdquo; album. The first track of the album, recorded in 1960 in a live show in Paris, documents a dramatic moment in the history of modern music. The European concert goers were expecting the dreamy world of Kind of Blue and some pleasant show tunes. They didn&amp;rsquo;t know that John Coltrane was going to unleash the furious sounds of the future to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tori_amos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tori_amos/</guid>
      <description> I don’t believe you are leaving cause me and Charles Manson like the same ice cream - Tori Amos, Tears in Your Hands
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/blockchainjoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/blockchainjoke/</guid>
      <description>Anthropologists discovered that islanders in South Pacific have been using blockchains for thousands of years. All transactions are recorded by carving patterns on tree trunks, whose integrity is enforced by solving hard problems such as 12/5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/einsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/einsum/</guid>
      <description>Just discovered that python&amp;rsquo;s numerical package has a function for Einstein summation for tensors. In the past, you need that for cosmology. These days you use them for neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading comic books as brain lesions</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 23:10:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/comic/</guid>
      <description>I can’t be the only one who has trouble reading comic books. I have problems interpolating between the panels, and I find it hard to recognise the characters. In other words, I don’t know how one panel is related to the next, and I don’t know who’s who. Reading comic books to me is like a simulation of cortical lesions. It induces a mild form of akinetopsia(deficit in the perception of motion) and prosopagnosia (deficit in the perception of faces).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pendulum/</guid>
      <description>The plot of Umberto Eco&amp;rsquo;s novel Foucault&amp;rsquo;s Pendulum involves two publishers: Garamond and Manutius. Both names refer to figures in the history of printing: Claude Garamond designed the Garamond font in the 16th century, while Aldus Manutius was a famous 15th century printer who invented italic type, a few punctuation marks, and the pocketbook format. This might be a joke because both names are relatable to Apple. The Garamond font was used in Apple&amp;rsquo;s logo, and Aldus Co.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cobbler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:19:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/cobbler/</guid>
      <description>This cobbler has remained in the same corner in Taipei for decades. The neighbourhood has experienced dramatic changes. Old apartments have been replaced by modern buildings. Traditional food stalls became hipster coffee shops. But this cobbler is apparently frozen in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/turing/</guid>
      <description> Turing once dreamed that he was a Turing machine. When he woke up, he wondered if it was him who dreamed of being a Turing machine, or if it was a Turning machine which dreamed that it was Turing - a koan from a programming book published in Taiwan)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/poincare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:45:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/poincare/</guid>
      <description>In a recent trip to Paris, my wife and I visited the Montparnasse Cemetery, hoping to find the tomb of the mathematician Évariste Galois. We were disappointed to learn that although Galois was indeed buried in the cemetery, he was buried in a common grave and the burial site can no longer be identified. However, we were delighted to have found the family tomb of Henri Poincaré.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/shutterspeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/shutterspeed/</guid>
      <description>What is the shutter speed of human vision? A new paper claims that at extremely low light condition, it can be as long as 0.6 second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/retina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/retina/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to see an optometrist. As he examined my eye with a strong light, I was amazed that I saw an image of the blood vessels on the retina. This phenomenon is called the entoptic image. It was first described by Purkinje about 200 years ago. I read about it in “How we perceive our own retina” by Kuno Kirschfeld (published in Proc. Bio. Sci.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:25:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</guid>
      <description>I saw this book in the Melbourne Rare Book Fair. To anyone who can read Chinese, this looks like the practice book of a young child starting to learn to write. The characters are intelligible, but the writer clearly has not mastered the basic principles. If Chinese characters are people, these little guys are seriously deformed. Some have really big heads, some have tiny feet, most of them look like zombies walking with their body parts dangling, ready to fall off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:18:50 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</guid>
      <description>Michel Foucault’s Madness and Civilization opens with the poetic imagery of Ship of Fools. But what is the ship of fools? Apparently it all started with this book. I saw it in an exhibition of books sharing the theme of traveling at the library of Monash University. This is the latin edition of Ship of Fools by German humanist Sebastian Brant, published in 1497. The illustrations are by Albretch Durer (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which department threw out a freaking VAX?</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:01:17 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vax/</guid>
      <description>On university corridors, you inevitably see old equipments lying around. But which department threw out an entire freaking VAX?
    Those must be the famous &amp;ldquo;blinkenlights&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 18:48:32 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</guid>
      <description>This is the famous world map by the 15th century monk Fra Mauro. I saw it in Museo Galileo in Florence. Unfortunately it was a replica. The real thing is in Venice. I found it very difficult to recognize landmarks on the map because the orientation is very different from our modern convention. North is down. South is up.
         Here’s a puzzle: What’s this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereoscopic photography on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 23:45:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/2ds/</guid>
      <description>I received a Nintendo 2DS as a gift. The 2DS is a downgraded version of the Nintendo 3DS handheld game console. To cut price (2DS retails at about $150 AUD), Nintendo removed the 3D display but interestingly it still has a pair of front facing cameras. The photos are saved into the .MPO format, and can be loaded and processed by many programs running on computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:20:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/elm/</guid>
      <description>Have I neglected the backyard garden this much in the last few weeks? This morning when I opened the backdoor, I was surprised to see the grounds covered by mysterious coin-shaped objects. They were clearly seeds — seeds wearing papery, gossamer skirts. Sure, I have seen them before, but not so many all at once.
         They parachuted from my neighbor’s golden elm tree - an elm native to northern America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/word_puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:03:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/word_puzzle/</guid>
      <description>A friend told me about Su Hui&amp;rsquo;s Star Gauge. It is is a matrix poem composed in the 4th century by the Chinese poetess Su Hui. The characters are arranged in a 29x29 matrix. The submatrices can be read in different directions, producing (apparently) 3000 poems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/don_quixote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/don_quixote/</guid>
      <description> The reason of the unreason with which my reason is afflicted so weakens my reason that with reason I murmur at your beauty - Don Quixote
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color-vision-historical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 19:04:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color-vision-historical/</guid>
      <description>What was the first time that we know that non-human animals have color vision? From what I can find, the first person who scientifically came to that conclusion was John Lubbock in 1888. What was so strange about it was that he studied Daphnia - a plankton (!). He discovered that the plankton was attracted to yellow light, but not to white light. Lubbock also reasoned that insects must have color vision, but was not able to scientifically demonstrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/journal/</guid>
      <description>We need a journal that publishes papers in the style of the 18th century: long title, flowery prose, kudos to King and church, and extreme modesty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/analog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/analog/</guid>
      <description>analogmuseum.org is a website about analog computers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/visual_cortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/visual_cortex/</guid>
      <description>What is known as the visual cortex today was thought to be the site of &amp;ldquo;philoprogenitivty” (parental love) in phrenology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon3/</guid>
      <description> Really. Hey, like Godzilla always sez to Mothra — why don’t we go eat some place? — Inherent Vice by Thomas Pynchon
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bond/</guid>
      <description>Choose your next private key carefully, Mr. Bond. It may be your last. Do you expect me to talk? No. I expect you to prime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pynchon2/</guid>
      <description> No worries, it’s on the house, as the TV antenna man always sez — Thomas Pynchon in Inherent Vice
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/ground-squirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 18:26:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/ground-squirrel/</guid>
      <description>I took these photos for a research project while I was a student at UC San Diego. They are the skull and the brain of the California ground squirrel (Spermophilus beecheyi)
         </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
