<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 08:53:25 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/brewster-bmm8cru2hysbehj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 08:53:25 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/brewster-bmm8cru2hysbehj/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Italo Calvino’s If on a winters night a traveller. One chapter is particularly interesting because it draws heavily on the imagery of optics (one of Calvino&amp;rsquo;s obsessions). It makes a reference to the 19th century British scientist David Brewster for his invention of the kaleidoscope. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read about Brewster before so I had to look him up. He was so much more than the inventor of kaleidoscope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:04:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/eco_note_taking/</guid>
      <description>I was reading about the Emacs org-roam mode, and came across the Zettelkasten method of notetaking. I hadn’t seen this term before, but the idea of taking notes with cross-referenced index cards sounded familiar. Where did I read about it? Ah yes&amp;hellip; in Umberto Eco’s Foucault’s Pendulum, the main character Casaubon (an ex-academic who makes a living as a “detective of knowledge”) uses boxes of index cards to keep track of ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/review_count_zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:18:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/review_count_zero/</guid>
      <description>Finished William Gibson’s Count Zero. I like William Gibson. There are things that he did extremely well in this novel. But it doesn’t work. The three main threads of narrative are all interesting ideas by themselves, but they don’t add up to a meaningful big picture. In the end, I don’t understand why anything happened. I was planning to read Mona Lisa Overdrive after this one, but maybe not. The second half of Count Zero seems too clumsily written for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/new_rose_hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:14:05 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/new_rose_hotel/</guid>
      <description>Europe was a dead museum
 from William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s New Rose Hotel. Clearly an homage to William S. Burroughs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 12:10:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/countzero_turing/</guid>
      <description>So maybe you’ll get the Turing machine after your ass
 Count Zero by William Gibson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:55:01 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/inspector_anelis/</guid>
      <description>I like this little episode in Umberto Eco&amp;rsquo;s Foucault&amp;rsquo;s Pendulum. In Chapter 53, one of the main characters Casaubon, a scholar of European history, unexpectedly ran into Inspector De Angelis in a library. He was surprised that the policeman checked out the same book that he was looking for. Why are you reading such an esoteric book? The policeman answered: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m off duty, I like to browse in libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:01:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/v_holmes/</guid>
      <description>In V., Chapter 14, Pynchon made passing references to the Dreyfus Affair - a social controversy that divided France near the end of the 19th century. Just by coincidence, I read something about it earlier this year. The Father Brown story &amp;ldquo;The Duel of Dr Hirsch&amp;rdquo; by G.K. Chesterton is a very odd detective story, because it&amp;rsquo;s really a commentary on the Dreyfus Affairs.
The other historical figure that plays a more significant role in V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 09:37:39 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/daemon_book/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of an interesting book:Bedeviled: A Shadow History of Demons in Science, about thought experiments in science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 18:33:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/stats_book/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recommended a book called &amp;ldquo;Computer Age Statistical Inference&amp;rdquo; by Efron &amp;amp; Hastie. I love the organization. Part I - classical stuff. Part II - Early computer-age methods. Part III - 21st century topics. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the type of textbooks that we need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:42:34 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/finished_v/</guid>
      <description>Finished reading: V. by Thomas Pynchon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 01:35:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>An obscure historical note from Thomas Pyhcon’s novel V.: there is a Chopin museum in the Spanish island of Mallorca, where you can see a cast of Frédéric Chopin’s hand. Chopin spent a winter there in 1838.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 01:32:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/perec/</guid>
      <description>I found this 2019 New York Times article about the fascinating work of French writer Georges Perec. Note that Donald Kunth called his Life: A User&amp;rsquo;s Manual “perhaps the greatest 20th century novel”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:28:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/github_literature/</guid>
      <description>I want to see writers use GitHub for literary experimentation. It can be a new form of ergodic literature. Imagine a novel released as a GitHub repo. Readers can read it. They can check out all the branches to explore parallel universes of alternative plots. They can read the revision history as a meta-novel, to learn about the writing process. And of course, they can make new versions of the novel by merging branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 23:32:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/tagliacozzi/</guid>
      <description>In Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s first novel V., there is a subplot involving rhinoplasty. A surgeon in the story (“being a conservative”) refers to his own profession as the “Art of Tagliacozzi”. This is reference to the 16th century surgeon Gaspare Tagliacozzi, who pioneered surgical techniques for nasal reconstruction. He was a professor of anatomy at the Archiginnasio of Bologna, whose famous anatomical theatre houses a statue of Tagliacozzi holding a nose. I visited Bologna in 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 23:23:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/color_book/</guid>
      <description>Bright Earth by Philip Ball is a remarkably multidisciplinary book about color. In a chapter about renaissance art, he described the technique of cangiantismo, which is most famously associated with the work of Michangelo. Wikipedia’s entry explains: “Cangiante is characterized by a change in color necessitated by an original color&amp;rsquo;s darkness or lightness limitation”. The effect is unnatural but it’s what fascinates me most about Michangelo’s paintings.
This article explains how the technique was used in contemporary art such as Monster Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 01:13:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/vonnegut_pynchon/</guid>
      <description>It’s interesting that two favourite writers of mine had worked for big tech companies. Kurt Vonnegut worked for the PR department of GE. His portrayal of the genius scientist in Cat’s Cradle was based on his interview of Nobel Laureate Irving Langmuir of GE Research. Thomas Pynchon was a tech writer for Boeing. Yoyodyne, a defence contractor in The Crying of Lot 49, is a caricature of Boeing.
Dec 4th 2020 update: I also learned that William Gaddis worked for Kodak and IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/bowles/</guid>
      <description> In other parts of Africa, you are aware of the earth beneath your feet, of the vegetation and the animals; all power seems concentrated in the earth. In North Africa the earth becomes the less important part of the landscape because you find yourself constantly raising your eyes to look at the sky. In the arid landscape the sky is the final arbiter. - Paul Bowles
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:39:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/kerouac/</guid>
      <description>Anticipating the next release of macOS (10.16; Big Sur), I started to read the novel Big Sur by Jack Kerouac. It&amp;rsquo;s very interesting to me that in Chapter 12, Kerouac went to visit Neal Cassady, who was living in the Santa Clara Valley (more precisely, 1047 E. Santa Clara Street). So, in the late 50&amp;rsquo;s, Neal Cassady was practically living in today&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley. I had never associated with Silicon Valley with the counterculture movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Collection of Sand - essays by Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/calvino_sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/calvino_sand/</guid>
      <description>Collection of Sand is a collection of book reviews, exhibition reviews and travelogues that Italo Calvino wrote in the 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s. The quality varies. The best of them are unsurprisingly ekphrastic essays where Calvino described gardens, historical sites, and paintings in exquisite details. Those where he tried to regurgitate scientific or historical knowledge from academic books are less inspiring. But still, it is the variety of things that Calvino cared to write about that charms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:25:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/chinese/</guid>
      <description>I saw this book in the Melbourne Rare Book Fair. To anyone who can read Chinese, this looks like the practice book of a young child starting to learn to write. The characters are intelligible, but the writer clearly has not mastered the basic principles. If Chinese characters are people, these little guys are seriously deformed. Some have really big heads, some have tiny feet, most of them look like zombies walking with their body parts dangling, ready to fall off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 23:18:50 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/fools/</guid>
      <description>Michel Foucault’s Madness and Civilization opens with the poetic imagery of Ship of Fools. But what is the ship of fools? Apparently it all started with this book. I saw it in an exhibition of books sharing the theme of traveling at the library of Monash University. This is the latin edition of Ship of Fools by German humanist Sebastian Brant, published in 1497. The illustrations are by Albretch Durer (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 18:48:32 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/framauromap/</guid>
      <description>This is the famous world map by the 15th century monk Fra Mauro. I saw it in Museo Galileo in Florence. Unfortunately it was a replica. The real thing is in Venice. I found it very difficult to recognize landmarks on the map because the orientation is very different from our modern convention. North is down. South is up.
         Here’s a puzzle: What’s this?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
