<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photo on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/photo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photo on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Hsin-Hao Yu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:19:11 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/photo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Cobbler</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/cobbler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:19:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/cobbler/</guid>
      <description>This cobbler has remained in the same corner in Taipei for decades. The neighbourhood has experienced dramatic changes. Old apartments have been replaced by modern buildings. Traditional food stalls became hipster coffee shops. But this cobbler is apparently frozen in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying tribute to Henri Poincaré in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/poincare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:45:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/poincare/</guid>
      <description>In a recent trip to Paris, my wife and I visited the Montparnasse Cemetery, hoping to find the tomb of the mathematician Évariste Galois. We were disappointed to learn that although Galois was indeed buried in the cemetery, he was buried in a common grave and the burial site can no longer be identified. However, we were delighted to have found the family tomb of Henri Poincaré. Apparently, mathematicians have developed the tradition of leaving their used Paris Metro tickets on the stone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipitous photoshopping</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photoshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 23:55:20 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/photoshop/</guid>
      <description>The unusually thick glasses on the windows of the Old Art building in Melbourne University seem to be hand-polished, whose uneven surfaces naturally distort the view into an American expressionist painting.
     The historic building of the Drum Theatre in Dandenong, Victoria was reflected on a modern office building across the road. The reflective windows reconfigured the image into an incongruent mosaic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereoscopic photography on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 23:45:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2ds/</guid>
      <description>I received a Nintendo 2DS as a gift. The 2DS is a downgraded version of the Nintendo 3DS handheld game console. To cut price (2DS retails at about $150 AUD), Nintendo removed the 3D display but interestingly it still has a pair of front facing cameras. The photos are saved into the .MPO format, and can be loaded and processed by many programs running on computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panoramic</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/panorama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 01:38:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/panorama/</guid>
      <description>Along the River During the Qingming Festival (清明上河圖) is a 12th-century classic Chinese painting depicting the imperial capital on a particularly busy day. Painted on a long scroll, the &amp;ldquo;panorama&amp;rdquo; is too wide to be appreciated in its entirity. The viewers are invited to view only a small section of the painting at the time and immerse themselves in the details.
    I have been interested in duplicating this effect with photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The old man and the vacuum tubes</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/akihabara/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:59:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/akihabara/</guid>
      <description>During a trip to Tokyo in 2013, I found an opportunity to visit the Akihabara district. This area is world famous for its high concentration of shops selling the latest models of computers, game consoles, gadgets, and other geeky items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The California ground squirrel</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/ground-squirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 18:26:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/ground-squirrel/</guid>
      <description>I took these photos for a research project while I was a student at UC San Diego. They are the skull and the brain of the California ground squirrel (Spermophilus beecheyi)
         </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
