<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Hsin-Hao Yu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Collection of Sand - essays by Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/calvino_sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/calvino_sand/</guid>
      <description>Collection of Sand is a collection of book reviews, exhibition reviews and travelogues that Italo Calvino wrote in the 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s. The quality varies. The best of them are unsurprisingly ekphrastic essays where Calvino described gardens, historical sites, and paintings in exquisite details. Those where he tried to regurgitate scientific or historical knowledge from academic books are less inspiring. But still, it is the variety of things that Calvino cared to write about that charms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several places in the music of Charles Ives</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/charles_ives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 21:38:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/charles_ives/</guid>
      <description>Charles Ives (1874–1954) is the quintessential American composer. Some of his compositions are as American as cherry pie. Take the Country Band March (1905), for example. It brings you straight to the turn-of-the century America:
  It’s a collage of folk tunes, patriotic songs, and marching band music, but you only hear a melody briefly, and then it’s either interrupted rudely or mutated gracefully into another. Very often two or three motifs are played simultaneously so you can’t decide which one to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>