<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vision on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/tags/vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vision on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) Hsin-Hao Yu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/tags/vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Collection of Sand - essays by Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/calvino_sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 08:49:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/calvino_sand/</guid>
      <description>Collection of Sand is a collection of book reviews, exhibition reviews and travelogues that Italo Calvino wrote in the 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s. The quality varies. The best of them are unsurprisingly ekphrastic essays where Calvino described gardens, historical sites, and paintings in exquisite details. Those where he tried to regurgitate scientific or historical knowledge from academic books are less inspiring. But still, it is the variety of things that Calvino cared to write about that charms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many photons get into your eyes?</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/photons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 20:31:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/photons/</guid>
      <description>A recent paper shows that our vision is so sensitive to light that human subjects can detect the presence of one single photon shot into their retinas. While scientists have been trying to establish the lower limit of visual sensitivity for a very long time, and it is generally accepted that a small number of photons are sufficient for detection since the 40’s, new advances in quantum optics finally allow us to manipulate light at single photon precision, and it is the first time that direct evidence for single photon sensitivity is demonstrated in a psychological experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The marmoset visual area DM for dummies</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/areadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 20:07:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/areadm/</guid>
      <description>The visuotopic map of the marmoset dorsomedial visual cortex (area DM; see references) is sufficiently complex that it is probably worthwhile to design a few visual aides to make it more intuitive. The figure above is my first attempt. In this figure, DM is divided into three segments, with the most medial segment representing central upper visual field (nose and eye of Sir Isaac Newton), the middle segment representing the entire lower visual field, and the medial segment representing the peripheral upper visual field (the forehead and hair of Newton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The retinotopic map of marmoset V1</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/marmosetv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 18:51:42 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/marmosetv1/</guid>
      <description>I created this figure to illustrate the retinotopic map of the primary visual cortex of the marmoset. The eccentricity contours are plotted in red, and polar angles are in blue. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create it in 3D so that you can rotate it around and see it from different angles. This is how you do it:
 Download ParaView, the open source 3D data visualization package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar opposite</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/polar-opposite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 17:28:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/polar-opposite/</guid>
      <description>This figure illustrates the direction tuning curves of two motion sensitive neurons recorded in the primary visual cortex. The two neurons were so close to each other that their activities could be picked up by the same electrode. Interestingly they preferred polar opposite directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PSY3310/Human vision as frequency filters</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edupsy3310-fourier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:32:20 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edupsy3310-fourier/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrations:  The reconstruction of Mona Lisa video. A blog post I wrote about the Fourier transform trick. Youtube video: Nobel laureates David Hubel and Torsten Wiesel recording neurons in cat&amp;rsquo;s V1.  Suggested readings: Fourier transform  An introduction to two-dimensional fast Fourier transforms and their applications by Rzeszotarski et al. (1983). Fourier transforms and frequency-domain processing (Chapter 5 of Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing: A Practical Approach with Examples in Matlab by Solomon &amp;amp; Breckon, 2011)  Suggested readings: programming  See this web page from UCSB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: RAD2092/Physiology of Visual Pathways</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edurad2092-visual-cortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:26:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edurad2092-visual-cortex/</guid>
      <description> Central disorders of vision in humans by Girkin &amp;amp; Miller (2001): a review of what happens if different parts of the visual cortex are damaged. &amp;ldquo;Superimposed hemifields in primary visual cortex of achiasmic individuals&amp;rdquo; by Sinha &amp;amp; Meng (2012, Neuron 75): Newton vs. Descartes on the organization of the optic chiasm. Youtube video demonstrating how Hubel &amp;amp; Wiesel mapped V1 receptive fields.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: RAD2092/The eye and the retina</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edurad2092-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:23:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/edurad2092-eye/</guid>
      <description> Animal Eyes by Land &amp;amp; Nilsson is a very nice little book about the fascinating variety of eye structures found in nature. Youtube video about the &amp;ldquo;connectome&amp;rdquo; of the retina  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PHY3012/Plasticity in the visual system in development</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/eduphy3012-plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 14:02:22 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/eduphy3012-plasticity/</guid>
      <description>Interesting  A man with only half a brain A study of a man who recovered vision after decades of being blind: Fine et al. (2003) Long-term deprivation affects visual perception and cortex. Nat. Neurosci. 6, p915. How Utter Darkness Could Heal Lazy Eye: related to ocular dominance critical period. Giving blind people sight illuminates the brain’s secrets  General review  Anderson et al (2011) Do children really recover better?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Material: PHY3111/Color Vision</title>
      <link>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/eduphy3111-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 13:33:14 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hhyu2020.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/posts/eduphy3111-color/</guid>
      <description>Interesting articles  Impossible colours: You can experience colours that you have never seen before. Some women are tetrachromatic. They can see more colours than most people can. The rainbow does not contain all the colours that we can see. For example, magenta.  Dressgate  Disrobing the dress:A very detailed webpage about the dress. Lessons from the dress: by vision scientist Pascal Wallisch. The science of why no one agrees on the color of this dress: an article on Wired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>