<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychology on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psychology on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 22:54:13 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More detective stories involving perceptual psychology</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2023_10_09_more_colorblindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 22:54:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2023_10_09_more_colorblindness/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blog post, I reviewed Ellery Queen&amp;rsquo;s classic detective novel The Greek Coffin Mystery (1932), which manages to involve color blindness in its puzzles. But I am not done yet! I have a couple more.
On one hand, it feels to me that color blindness is gimmicky as a plot device. A mystery writer must be quite desperate for new ideas if she or he has to turn to perceptual psychology (or any branch of specialized knowledge, for that matter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A vision scientist&#39;s review of The Greek Coffin Mystery by Ellery Queen (1932)</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2023_10_04_ellery_queen_greek_coffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 07:47:33 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/2023_10_04_ellery_queen_greek_coffin/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t think mystery novels by Ellery Queen are popular in western countries anymore, but they are still read in Asia. When I was a PhD student, every time I had to travel from my home country Taiwan to the USA, I would buy an Ellery Queen novel at the airport bookstore. This way, I could land in LAX with a solved mystery. Ellery Queen novels are substantial books with very complex plots - perfect for long flights because uninterrupted concentration is needed to tackle them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/10_04_2023_guitar_diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:19:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/10_04_2023_guitar_diary/</guid>
      <description>Guitar learning diary: As I learn to play the guitar, I realised that I might be able to make musical associations without mental awareness. It&amp;rsquo;s probably because I am not familiar enough with the language of music to surface musical feelings to a conscious level. For example, yesterday, I tried to play some dominant 9 chords in a book. I was learning the fingering so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t attending to the sounds of the chords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/teller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 20:48:35 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/teller/</guid>
      <description>My family has been watching the Penn &amp;amp; Teller: Fool Us TV series. I was reminded of a 2008 paper published in Nature Review Neuroscience about the psychological aspects of magic. Teller was listed as a co-author (among several well-known magicians). There is a very remarkable sentence in the paper: &amp;ldquo;One of the authors of this Perspective (referring to Apollo Robbins) is a professional thief.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
