<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Cortically Magnified</title>
    <link>https://www.hhyu.org/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Cortically Magnified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 22:33:51 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hhyu.org/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simple exercises with grep, sed and awk in org-mode</title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/shell_regexp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 22:33:51 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/posts/shell_regexp/</guid>
      <description>For text processing, I had never bothered to learn classic Unix tools such as sed and awk, because I can always use Python&amp;#39;s regular expression library. The syntax of sed and awk just appeared to be too arcane to me. However, recently I realize that for many simple ad-hoc tasks, even writing a Python script is too much overhead. This motivated me to learn to use regular expressions directly in the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/grammar_of_tree-wvvmunibcjh1tn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:41:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/grammar_of_tree-wvvmunibcjh1tn/</guid>
      <description>In the 70&amp;rsquo;s, it was fashionable for intellectuals to abuse the term &amp;ldquo;grammar&amp;rdquo; to refer to any underlying principles. In one of his essays, Italo Calvino used the term &amp;ldquo;the grammar of tree&amp;rdquo; to refer to&amp;hellip;. essentially developmental plant biology. I thought that was pretentious. But heh, in R programming, people are talking about the grammar of graphics or data manipulations. It&amp;rsquo;s fashionable to call functions &amp;ldquo;verbs&amp;rdquo; again. Hello, structuralism!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:54:56 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/pythonpynchon/</guid>
      <description>Idea: a Python dialect called Pynchon (after Thomas Pynchon). A pynchonic code is probably not very pythonic. Brevity is highly discouraged. Variable names should be all puns. In fact, Pynchon should be a concatenative language like Forth. This way, statements can be chained together into a longer and longer statement&amp;hellip; until the entire program is one single statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 23:29:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hhyu.org/micro/orgmode_literate/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I rewrote my Emacs config script in the style of literate programming. Emacs has a markup language (org-mode) that makes it easy to mix rich text with code. I did it mostly out of curiosity. At that time, I didn’t know if writing something as trivial as a config file this way was a good idea in terms of practicality. After a month of tweaking, I am now convinced that It was helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
